<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>M. Watson Mulkey</title>
    <description>Welcome!</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>A Constant State Of Wip</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ive-tried-to-be-very-aware-about-developing-back-programming-habits&quot;&gt;I’ve tried to be very aware about developing back programming habits.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it seems like many arguments and disagreements about what constitutes “bad” habits are more pedantic than practical, successful coding and development hinge on detail and planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I’m a big fan of getting my hands dirty. In the low-stakes game of a personal Jekyll blog, I enjoy the constant git pushing and the changes. Messing up, figuring out why something is broken, and then going in and trying to fix it is part of the thrill of coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a time for proper prior planning, and there’s a time for playing in the dirt. Therefore, forgive me these my many iterations––I promise they’re not a thinly veiled attempt at padding my commit history.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/A-Constant-State-of-WIP</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/A-Constant-State-of-WIP</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Into It Over It And Whether Propogation Always Equals Success</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Evan Thomas Weiss wrote and recorded a song a week for an entire year. The anthology known as “52 Weeks” was an opening salvo for a career that (so far) has proven to be incredibly prolific, spanning multiple bands, labels, collaborators, while maintaining a sound a feel that feels native to it’s creator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weiss has said in so many words and in as many interviews “If you want to get good at music, you just have to write music.” It’s tempting to want to heed Weiss’ advice, but is the path to notoriety, re tweets, mentions (or whichever trappings of success one acknowledges) found simply through proliferation, or are the geniuses of music and the unicorns of business guilty of being romanticized by the same survivorship bias?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In world that increasingly asks for our attention, is propagating the idea that effort expended always corresponds neatly and consistently the measurable progress seems unfordable. As we continue to luxuriously drown in new content that spans all mediums, does the content that we create to better our craft become a detriment to others?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/Into-It-Over-It-and-Whether-Propogation-Always-Equals-Success</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/Into-It-Over-It-and-Whether-Propogation-Always-Equals-Success</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Glad Youre Here</title>
        <description>If you manage to find your way here while this post is still up, you're either a friend, curious, bored, or (depending on your outlook on life) lucky. 

I'm planning on making this a space where I get by with myself, and with a little help with my friends. 

-Watson
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/Glad-youre-here</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/Glad-youre-here</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
