<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>M. Watson Mulkey</title>
    <description>Welcome!</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Book Notes Hooked By Nir Eyal</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;book-notes-hooked-how-to-build-habit-forming-products-by-nir-eyal&quot;&gt;Book Notes: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Hooked-How-Build-Habit-Forming-Products/dp/1591847788/&quot;&gt;Hooked: How to Build Habit-Forming Products by Nir Eyal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-was-recently-given-a-task-to-power-through-some-books-for-both-personal-retention-and-public-good-i-thought-id-borrow-a-dance-move-from-derek-sivers-and-keep-public-notes-on-them-these-notes-will-be-updated-when-i-push-to-the-blog-and-will-follow-along-with-me-in-the-book-when-i-finish-a-book-ill-try-and-do-some-big-takeaways&quot;&gt;I was recently given a task to power through some books. For both personal retention and public good, I thought I’d borrow a dance move from &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/book&quot;&gt;Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt; and keep public notes on them. These notes will be updated when I push to the blog and will follow along with me in the book. When I finish a book, I’ll try and do some big takeaways.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;amassing-millions-of-users-is-no-longer-enough-companies-increasingly-find-that-their-economic-value-is-a-function-of-the-strength-of-the-habits-they-create-pg-2&quot;&gt;“Amassing millions of users is no longer enough. Companies increasingly find that their economic value is a function of the strength of the habits they create.” pg 2&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This caught my eye, but I’m up in the air about the universality of it at this point. This might be more true for companies that take percentages (ride sharing, transactions) than companies who survive on ad revenue (Facebook, Twitter). Google seems to the be an exception. Happy to be prove wrong about that (which, presumably is what this book will do.) &amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nirandfar.com/&quot;&gt;nirandfar.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-hook-model&quot;&gt;The Hook Model&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trigger (internal/ external), Action, Variable, Reward. &amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;feedback-loops-are-all-around-us-but-predictable-ones-dont-create-desire-the-unsurprising-response-of-your-fridge-light-turning-on-when-you-open-the-door-doesnt-drive-you-to-keep-opening-it-again-and-again-pg-8&quot;&gt;“Feedback Loops are all around us, but predictable ones don’t create desire. The unsurprising response of your fridge light turning on when you open the door doesn’t drive you to keep opening it again and again.” Pg 8&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🤔 &amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;research-shows-that-levels-of-the-neurotransmitter-dopamine-surge-when-the-brain-is-expecting-a-reward-introducing-variability-multiplies-the-effect-creating-a-focused-state-which-suppresses-the-areas-of-the-brain-associated-with-judgment-and-reason-while-activating-parts-associated-with-wanting-and-desire-pg-8-9&quot;&gt;“Research shows that levels of the neurotransmitter dopamine surge when the brain is expecting a reward. Introducing variability multiplies the effect, creating a focused state, which suppresses the areas of the brain associated with judgment and reason while activating parts associated with wanting and desire.” pg 8-9&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow. The “loot box” phenomenon that’s being integrated into all aspects of games makes a lot of sense given this research. This might also be why games RPG’s are so compelling in the first place. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cracked.com/article_18461_5-creepy-ways-video-games-are-trying-to-get-you-addicted.html&quot;&gt;Here’s an article from Cracked about this specifically&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;recently-a-blog-reader-emailed-me-if-it-cant-be-used-for-evil-its-not-a-superpower-pg-11&quot;&gt;“Recently, a blog reader emailed me, “If it can’t be used for evil, it’s not a superpower.”” pg 11&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whoa. &amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;habit-forming-products-change-user-behavior-and-create-unprompted-user-engagement-pg-17&quot;&gt;“Habit forming products change user behavior and create unprompted user engagement.” pg 17&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t help but think of this in terms of software that allow for short cutting workflows in favor of efficiency. I still reach for my Alfred snippets, and remember my Front workflows quite well. It seems like software used to create habit by simplifying process is perhaps trying to do the same thing. &amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;a-business-is-worth-the-sum-of-its-future-profits--pg-19&quot;&gt;“A business is worth the sum of its future profits. -pg 19”&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A succinct summary &amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Fostering habits creates a higher Customer Lifetime Value. pg. 19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2012/11/04/should-your-startup-go-freemium/evernote-smile-graph/&quot;&gt;The Evernote Smile Graph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;users-who-continuously-find-value-in-a-product-are-more-likely-to-tell-their-friends-about-it-pg-21-&quot;&gt;“Users who continuously find value in a product are more likely to tell their friends about it.” pg. 21 “&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For books about WOMM, I’d recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fizz-Harness-Power-Marketing-Growth/dp/0071835741/&quot;&gt;Fizz by Ted Wright&lt;/a&gt; and checking out Ted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TedWrightMedia&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;to-borrow-a-term-from-accounting-behaviors-are-lifo--last-in-first-out-in-other-words-the-habits-youve-most-recently-acquired-&quot;&gt;“To borrow a term from accounting, behaviors are LIFO – “Last in, first out.” In other words, the habits you’ve most recently acquired “&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;are-you-building-a-vitamin-or-a-painkiller-pg-32&quot;&gt;“Are you building a vitamin or a painkiller.” pg. 32&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ie; does this solve a problem, or does it satisfy you in some other way. &amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;emotions-particularly-negative-ones-are-powerful-internal-triggers-and-greatly-influence-our-daily-routines-feelings-of-boredom-loneliness-frustration-confusion-and-indecisiveness-often-instigate-a-slight-pain-or-irritation-and-prompt-an-almost-instantaneous-and-often-mindless-action-to-quell-the-negative-sensation-pg-48&quot;&gt;“Emotions, particularly negative ones, are powerful internal triggers and greatly influence our daily routines. Feelings of boredom, loneliness, frustration, confusion, and indecisiveness often instigate a slight pain or irritation and prompt an almost instantaneous and often mindless action to quell the negative sensation.” pg. 48&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YEP. This reminds of me of something Jason Pargin (aka Cracked’s David Wong) talks about on a couple of episodes of the Cracked podcast. How social apps are altering our brain chemistry to receive little dopamine hits from apps. The idea of these boredom triggers cycling into dopamine drops from the app use cements the process even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first heard the idea from Tim Ferriss, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/video/index/480240/adventures-in-grayscale/&quot;&gt;here’s a video talking about how to break cell phone addiction&lt;/a&gt;, and one of many articles talking about how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/3042046/the-science-behind-how-boredom-benefits-creative-thought&quot;&gt;boredom can be a good thing.&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;products-that-successfully-create-habits-sooth-the-users-pain-by-laying-claim-to-a-particular-feeling-to-do-so-product-designers-must-know-their-users-internal-triggersthat-is-the-pain-they-seek-to-solvethe-ultimate-goal-of-a-habit-forming-product-is-to-solve-the-users-pain-by-creating-an-association-so-that-the-user-identifies-the-companys-product-or-service-as-the-source-of-relief-pg-51-52&quot;&gt;“Products that successfully create habits sooth the user’s pain by laying claim to a particular feeling. To do so, product designers must know their users internal triggers––that is, the pain they seek to solve…The ultimate goal of a habit-forming product is to solve the user’s pain by creating an association so that the user identifies the company’s product or service as the source of relief.” pg. 51-52&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Lots of really good points about “declared preferences” vs. “revealed preferences”. What people say they want vs. what they actually do. I imagine this is what a lot of the fitness tracking industry is banking on. They don’t necessarily care if people lose weight, they want to sell them the satisfaction of feeling like they’re actively working on their weight. I suppose in this way they’re “vitamin” products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also ties into the idea of moral licensing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rjf8b_LLZ6g&quot;&gt;(here’s Gladwell giving a topical example)&lt;/a&gt; and the idea that we justify bad behavior based on past good behavior. The idea being that a fitness band/tracker gives you lots of emotional triggers, AND helps you do the things you want to do (break a diet), while still providing you the comfort of licensing away bad behavior. Pretty compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Just got an alert from the Hearthstone app on my phone: “A new ranked play season has begun! See how far you can climb this month!” Quite timely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading in Progress….&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/Book-Notes-Hooked-By-Nir-Eyal</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/Book-Notes-Hooked-By-Nir-Eyal</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Less Is More</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;im-trying-to-pair-down-a-bit&quot;&gt;I’m trying to pair down a bit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This most recent iteration of my apartment has a bit more square footage than I wanted and than I’m used to. My fear is that increased square footage means a heightened propensity to horde and collect. That’s an instinct that I’m genetically predisposed to, so the game is always trying to not add to the compulsion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it’s increasingly looking like I’ll be moving apartments, even if I stay in Greenville, I can’t help but cast a discerning eye over all the things that made the journey with me to this apartment in April. I like having books, but how many of them do I even lend out, let alone read. I like the framed pictures on mantle, but how would I present and keep them as memories as opposed to decoration? What would a small album that sat on a single table do for my appreciation for those photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I got rid of some clothes that I’d carried with me for the better part of a decade but had hardly ever worn. I listened to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://tim.blog/2017/04/16/marie-kondo/&quot;&gt;Tim Ferriss podcast that featured featured Marie Kondo&lt;/a&gt; that completely changed my thinking about holding on to sentimental items that have burdensome. The first was the idea that when things that were given to bring joy (for whatever reason) become a burden, then you’re not honoring the gift or the emotion that created it’s giving by holding on to it. The second was the idea of “thanking” items before you get rid of them. Taking time to appreciate the items for what they did for you, helped me let go of them in a way that didn’t feel like I was throwing something away. I donated two giant bags full of clothes to goodwill, and I haven’t missed any of those things since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m closing in on two weeks of work left, and it’s clear that life is about to shift for me. Now seems as good a time as any to re-evaluate my relationship with the things in my life, and make sure that I’m giving space, time and attention to the items that really matter. My hope is that my removing the clutter I can magnify the impact of the things that are truly special and worth holding on to.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/Less-is-more</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/Less-is-more</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Constant State Of Wip</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;ive-tried-to-be-very-aware-about-developing-bad-programming-habits&quot;&gt;I’ve tried to be very aware about developing bad programming habits.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it seems like many arguments and disagreements about what constitutes “bad” habits are more pedantic than practical, successful coding and development hinge on detail and planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I’m a big fan of getting my hands dirty. In the low-stakes game of a personal Jekyll blog, I enjoy the constant git pushing and the changes. Messing up, figuring out why something is broken, and then going in and trying to fix it is part of the thrill of coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a time for proper prior planning, and there’s a time for playing in the dirt. Therefore, forgive me these my many iterations––I promise they’re not a thinly veiled attempt at padding my commit history.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/A-Constant-State-of-WIP</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/A-Constant-State-of-WIP</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Into It Over It And Whether Propogation Always Equals Success</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Evan Thomas Weiss wrote and recorded a song a week for an entire year. The anthology known as “52 Weeks” was an opening salvo for a career that (so far) has proven to be incredibly prolific, spanning multiple bands, labels, collaborators, while maintaining a sound a feel that feels native to it’s creator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weiss has said in so many words and in as many interviews “If you want to get good at music, you just have to write music.” It’s tempting to want to heed Weiss’ advice, but is the path to notoriety, re tweets, mentions (or whichever trappings of success one acknowledges) found simply through proliferation, or are the geniuses of music and the unicorns of business guilty of being romanticized by the same survivorship bias?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In world that increasingly asks for our attention, is propagating the idea that effort expended always corresponds neatly and consistently the measurable progress seems unfordable. As we continue to luxuriously drown in new content that spans all mediums, does the content that we create to better our craft become a detriment to others?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/Into-It-Over-It-and-Whether-Propogation-Always-Equals-Success</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/Into-It-Over-It-and-Whether-Propogation-Always-Equals-Success</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Glad You're Here</title>
        <description>If you manage to find your way here while this post is still up, you're either a friend, curious, bored, or (depending on your outlook on life) lucky. 

I'm planning on making this a space where I get by with myself, and with a little help with my friends. 

-Watson
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/posts/Glad-you're-here</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/posts/Glad-you're-here</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
